<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RSVPApp</string>
    <string name="text1">
        Donald Trump, who built a mystique as the brash epitome of power, has never been more powerless to dictate his own fate. His reputation, future, and even perhaps the White House’s destiny, will on Wednesday be placed in the hands of 12 citizens of his native New York City, proving that not even once-and-possibly future commanders in chief are above the law. Seven men and five women jurors will retire for deliberations on Trump’s six-week hush money trial after Judge Juan Merchan instructs them on the law and their duties. No jury in American history has faced such a task — deciding whether a former president and presumptive major party nominee will be convicted of a crime. And while the jury, which can deliberate for as long as it needs, is bound to decide its verdict on 34 felony charges on the testimony and evidence in the case alone, its decision will reverberate across the nation and the world at a critical moment of the 2024 presidential election. The trial slogged toward its end on Tuesday in nearly 10 hours of closing arguments that burst into open hostility between rival lawyers. “You have to put aside the distractions, the press, the politics, the noise. Focus on the evidence and the logical inference that can be drawn from that evidence,” prosecution lawyer Joshua Steinglass told the jury. “In the interest of justice and in the name of the people of the state of the New York, I ask you to find the defendant guilty. Thank you.” Prosecutors accused the ex-president of “a conspiracy and a cover-up” and of betraying 2016 voters by illegally falsifying financial records to hide a hush money payment to adult film star Stormy Daniels before the election. Trump denies having an affair with Daniels and has pleaded not guilty in this first of four looming criminal cases — which may be the only one to go to trial before November’s election. In order to convict Trump, jurors must first decide that he falsified financial documents and did so with the express purpose of committing another crime. The ex-president watched quietly but intently in court Tuesday after days of firing off furious rhetorical assaults on the judge, prosecutors and the legal system. His lead defense counsel, Todd Blanche, tried to eviscerate the credibility of the case’s central witness, Michael Cohen, branding the self-described former Trump “thug” as the “GLOAT” — “the Greatest Liar of All Time,” while insisting there was no crime and no proof Trump orchestrated the plan to pay off Daniels. And conjuring a dark image that seemed to capture his client’s cynical view of democracy, Blanche said: “Every campaign in this country is a conspiracy to promote a candidate, a group of people who are working together to help somebody win.” The former president, who chose not to testify in his own defense, looked on, often with his arm draped across a chair, in the unusual position of having to leave others to speak for him. Trump has now spent six ignominious weeks breathing the stale air of a foreboding tower block of a courthouse that has dispensed justice to some of New York’s most storied murderers, crooks and Mafia dons. The yellowing white-wash, austere furniture and florescent lights that form the soulless abyss of America’s criminal justice system may have been an insult to the eyes of a developer who frequently boasts about the splendor of his buildings and is more at home under the glistening chandeliers and gold-leafed opulence of his multiple residencies. The final stages of any criminal trial reach a somber register as the gravity of the moment for the accused begins to come into view. In this case, which is entwined with a presidential election that will decide the country’s future, the consequences are even more profound. And there’s also a poignant personal dimension. The city where Trump made his name and reshaped the skyline while romping through the tabloid era of the 1980s is about to judge its estranged son. A political circus erupts outside the court Events outside the courtroom highlighted the rising stakes of the eventual verdict just five months from a currently tight election between Trump and President Joe Biden. Hollywood legend Robert De Niro showed up on behalf of the Biden campaign to blast “the loser Trump,” accompanied by some of the police officers beaten up by the ex-president’s mob in the US Capitol on January 6, 2021. The star of “Taxi Driver” and “Raging Bull” — a New York City icon in his own right — got into a quintessential finger-pointing standoff with a heckling bystander spreading misinformation about the assault on the Capitol.
    </string>
    <string name="text2">
        In recent years, advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) have driven optimization in systems and control engineering. We live in an age of big data, and AI and ML can analyze vast amounts of data in real time to improve efficiency and accuracy in data-driven decision-making processes. In control engineering, for example, AI algorithms can predict system behaviors and automatically adjust controls to optimize performance for increased efficiency and reliability.1 ML models, through their learning capabilities, continuously improve their predictions and decisions as they process more data, so systems can adapt to changing environments and operational conditions dynamically. This rapid adaptation improves the capabilities of existing systems and allows for the development of innovative solutions, such as autonomous vehicles and smart grids, that were once considered impractical.1 This article will explore the latest advancements in artificial intelligence and machine learning, including recent development of advanced algorithms. Deep Learning and Neural Networks Deep learning is a subset of machine learning that uses neural networks with many layers to analyze various forms of data. These advanced algorithms uncover patterns that traditional algorithms might miss and excel at processing and making sense of enormous datasets. Deep learning is behind advancements in areas such as image recognition and natural language processing (NLP).2 Two advancements in deep learning include convolutional neural networks (CNNs) and recurrent neural networks (RNNs). CNNs can easily parse visual information, so they’re widely used in image recognition systems. They simulate the way the human brain processes information by breaking down images into components and analyzing them layer by layer to identify patterns and features. RNNs are designed to understand sequential data, so they’re ideally suited for NLP tasks. They can remember previous inputs in the data sequence, which allows them to use predictive analytics to produce contextually informed text—a critical element in speech recognition and the generation of human language.3 These two emerging technologies are behind many AI innovations. In image and facial recognition technology, deep learning gives computers the ability to identify objects, faces and scenes with accuracy that rivals human perception, which has applications from medical imaging diagnostics to surveillance. Deep learning in natural language processing has helped develop applications that understand, interpret and generate human speech and language. NLP is behind advancements in voice recognition systems, translation services and conversational AI.3 Reinforcement Learning and Autonomous Systems Reinforcement learning (RL) allows machines or software—often referred to as "agents"—to learn to make decisions by trial and error. This process involves an agent interacting with its environment, performing actions and receiving feedback in the form of rewards or penalties. Over time, the agent learns to optimize its actions to maximize cumulative rewards, essentially learning from its experiences much as human beings do.4 Autonomous systems, particularly self-driving cars and robotics, are real-world applications of reinforcement learning. In self-driving cars, RL algorithms process multiple inputs of sensory data to make real-time decisions during navigation. In robotics, these algorithms allow autonomous robots to adapt to new tasks through interaction, learning how to manipulate objects or navigate environments independently.4 The increase in autonomous AI systems raises significant concerns regarding ethical considerations. Delegating important decisions to machines, particularly in situations involving human safety, presents dilemmas concerning accountability, privacy and job displacement. Making sure these systems make ethical decisions, free from biases embedded in their training data, is a big challenge. Engineers must take a balanced approach when designing these systems, considering both their transformative potential and the ethical imperatives to ensure they benefit society as a whole.5 Natural Language Processing Advancements As discussed above, NLP is driven by RNNs. NLP has changed how machines understand and interact with human language. These innovations are behind the development of conversational AI and chatbots that make interactions with digital systems more intuitive and human-like. Sophisticated NLP models let programs comprehend, generate and engage in conversations with users, providing assistance, gathering information and facilitating transactions.6 NLP is breaking down language barriers across the globe. Modern translation models use deep learning to provide translations that are accurate and capture the nuances and context of the original text. Sentiment analysis, another common use of NLP, allows machines to interpret and categorize opinions from text data. This can help organizations in the business world gain valuable insights into consumer attitudes and feelings.6 Voice recognition technology is also driven by advancements in NLP. Though such things used to exist only in science fiction, virtual assistants including Siri, Alexa and Google Assistant can now understand and respond to voice commands. Their practical applications include setting reminders and controlling smart home devices, making technology more interactive and accessible.
    </string>
    <string name="text3">
        Ultraconservative Iranian President Ebrahim Raisi was killed Sunday, along with his foreign minister, in a helicopter crash in Iran’s remote northwest, injecting fresh uncertainty as the country’s hardline clerical establishment navigates rising regional tensions and domestic discontent. The loss of two of Iran’s most influential political figures comes as the country buckles under significant economic and political strain, with tensions with nearby Israel at a dangerous high. Drone footage of the helicopter wreckage taken by the Red Crescent and carried on Iranian state media showed the crash site on a steep, wooded hillside, with little remaining of the helicopter beyond a blue and white tail. Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Khamenei – the final arbiter of domestic and foreign affairs in the country – announced five days of public mourning and confirmed that Iran’s First Vice President, Mohammad Mokhber, is now managing the executive branch. Raisi was Irans chief justice before rising to the Presidency. Murat Gok/Anadolu/Getty Images Sunday’s crash occurred as Raisi, 63, and Foreign Minister Hossein Amir-Abdollahian were returning from a ceremony for an opening of a dam on Iran’s border with Azerbaijan, state media reported. Among those onboard were three crew members, the governor of Eastern Azerbaijan province, an imam, Raisi’s head of security chief and a bodyguard, according to IRGC-run media outlet Sepah. The crash prompted an hours-long search-and-rescue operation with assistance from the European Union and Turkey among others, but emergency crews were hampered by the thick fog and plummeting temperatures. CNN confirmed the geolocation of the crash site to the mountainous region in Varzeghan, near the village of Uzi, in Iran’s East Azerbaijan province. The death of Raisi comes at a sensitive time domestically for Tehran and seven months into Israel’s war against Hamas in Gaza that has sent tensions soaring throughout the Middle East — and brought a decades-long shadow war between Israel and Iran out into the open. Last month, Iran launched an unprecedented drone and missile attack on Israel — its first ever direct attack on the country — in response to a deadly apparent Israeli airstrike on Iran’s consulate in Damascus. Under Raisi, Iran’s hardline leadership has faced significant challenges in recent years, convulsed by youth-led demonstrations against clerical rule and grim economic conditions. Iranian authorities have launched a widening crackdown on dissent since nationwide protests broke out over the 2022 death of a young woman in the custody of the country’s notorious morality police. Following the official announcement of Raisi’s death Monday, Iran’s government convened an “urgent meeting” as the clerical establishment, headed by Khamenei, prepare to appoint a new president they can throw their support behind. In this still from a video, an ambulance and other vehicles drive on a foggy road following a crash of a helicopter carrying Iras President Ebrahim Raisi, in Varzaqan, East Azerbaijan Province, Iran, on May 19. Iranian Red Crescent Society/Handout/Reuters The Iranian constitution also mandates that the three heads of the branches of government, including the Vice President, speaker of the parliament, and head of the judiciary, must arrange for an election and elect a new leader within 50 days of assuming the role of acting President. In a statement Monday, the president’s cabinet praised Raisi as a “hard-working and tireless” president who served the people of Iran to help advance and progress the country. “[He] stood by his promise and sacrificed his life for the nation,” the statement said. The cabinet, seeking to affirm calm in the country, also insisted there “will not be the slightest disturbance” in the administration of Iran in the wake of the deadly crash. On Monday, Iranian state broadcasters took to airing Islamic prayers in between news broadcasts, while a photo shared by IRNA showed that the chair that Raisi usually sits in was vacant and draped with a black sash in memory of the president. A president groomed for real power Raisi came to Iran’s presidency from the judiciary, where he drew attention from both the Iranian clerical elite and Western critics for his hardline approach to dissent and human rights in the country. In 2019 — the same year that Raisi became Iran’s chief justice — he was sanctioned by the US, citing his participation in the 1988 “death commission” as a prosecutor and a United Nations report on the judicial execution of at least nine children between 2018 and 2019. The Center for Human Rights in Iran (CHRI) has accused him of crimes against humanity for being part of the committee that oversaw the execution of up to 5,000 political prisoners in 1988. Raisi has never commented on these allegations. For Iran’s ruling establishment, though, Raisi seemed to be made in the image of the 1979 Islamic Revolution’s ideals, a guarantor of its continuation even as many chafed under its ultraconservative rules. In 2021, he was elected to the presidency in a contest heavily engineered by the Islamic Republic’s political elite so that he would run virtually unchallenged. Raisi’s inauguration was seen to signal the start of a new harder-line era in Iran. Many activists accused Iran’s clerical establishment of “selecting” rather than electing the next president in a poll designed to further entrench the power of the country’s hardline clerical rulers, despite the public’s calls for reforms. Overall voter turnout was 48.8% – the lowest since the establishment of the Islamic Republic.
    </string>
</resources>
